Guide to the Vardis Fisher Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- IV. December 1996 Acquisition, [circa 1930s-1980s]; 23.60' (27 boxes)
  - Audiovisual material and photographic film negatives
    - From Grant Fisher to Vardis Fisher, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504213)
    - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504221)
    - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504239)
    - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504247)
    - From Vardis Fisher to Grant Fisher, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504254)
    - From Grant Fisher to Vardis Fisher, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504262)
    - From W. Fisher to Vardis Fisher, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504270)
    - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504288)
    - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504296)
    - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504304)
    - Untitled, undated; 1 (Box 64, Item barcode 39002104504312)
    - Empty reel
    - Photographic film negatives
    - Photograph
  - Writings, clippings, and galley proofs, 10 (Box 65)
    Includes drafts and galley proofs of Vardis Fisher's "Thomas Wolfe As I Knew Him" and clippings of Vardis Fisher columns
  - Writings and photographs, 11 (Box 66)
    Includes drafts of several essays and typed notecards, as well as photographs of nature scenes
  - Writings and financial papers, 16 (Box 67)
    Includes typescript notes for "The Camps and Their People" and royalty statements
  - Correspondence, writings, financial papers, and photographs, 14 (Box 68)
    Includes Vardis and Opal Fisher correspondence, Christmas cards, page proof of "Mountain Man", reference cards, royalty statements, and photographs taken by Vardis Fisher
  - Correspondence, writings, and clippings, 11 (Box 69)
    Includes Vardis Fisher correspondence, typescript drafts of "Ourania Aphrodite", "Orphans in Gethsemane", and "Nina", reference cards, and newspaper clippings
  - Correspondence, writings, photographs, and clippings, 17 (Box 70)
    Includes Vardis and Opal Fisher correspondence, typescript drafts of "The Orphans" and "Heloise", miscellaneous photographs, and newspaper clippings
  - Writings and galley proofs, 7 (Box 71)
    Includes typescript drafts and galley proofs of "Orphans in Gethsemane" and a typescript draft of "Anyone is Divine: A Novel About Cleopatra" by Opal Laurel Holmes
  - Writings, 11 (Box 72)
    Includes typescript drafts of "The Idaho Encyclopedia", "In Tragic Life", "No Villain Need Be", and "Forgive Us Our Virtues"
  - Miscellaneous notes and material (Box 74)
    Includes a newspaper clipping, a mailing label, a note, three books, and a coffee filter
- V. December 1996 Acquisition, [circa 1940s-1960s]; 0.42' (1 box)
  Contains printed versions of shorter works by Fisher.
  Former call number: Uncat Za Ms 594.
  - Printed ephemera, 13 (Box 73)
    Contains writings by Fisher in such publications as "The Antioch Review", "South Dakota Review", "Inland", "The Rotarian: An International Magazine", and "Western America Literature"